If you don't STAND for something, you might FALL for anything.
Lions for Lambs is a action, adventure, drama film directed by Robert Redford.
Three stories told simultaneously in ninety minutes of real time: a Republican Senator who's a presidential hopeful gives an hour-long interview to a skeptical television reporter, detailing a strategy for
victory in Afghanistan; two special forces ambushed on an Afghani ridge await rescue as Taliban forces close in; a poli-sci professor at a California college invites a student to re-engage.
Janine Roth, played by Meryl Streep.
Senator Jasper Irving, played by Tom Cruise.
Dr. Stephen Malley, played by Robert Redford.
Todd Hayes, played by Andrew Garfield.
Ernest Rodriguez, played by Michael Peña.
Arian Finch, played by Derek Luke.
Lions for Lambs is a 2007 American war drama film directed by Robert Redford about the
connection between a platoon of United States soldiers in Afghanistan, a U.S.
senator, a reporter, and a Californian college professor.
It stars Redford, Tom Cruise, Meryl Streep, and Andrew
Garfield in his feature film debut.
It was the first Cruise/Wagner Productions film since the company joined with United
Artists subsequent to Cruise's falling out with Paramount Pictures in 2006.
With a title that alludes to incompetent leaders sending brave soldiers
into the slaughter of battle, the film takes aim at the U.S.
government's prosecution of the wars in the Middle East, showing three parallel stories: a senator who launches a new military strategy and details it to a
journalist, two soldiers involved in that operation, and their college professor trying to re-engage a promising student by telling him their story.
The film was written by Matthew Michael Carnahan.
It was released in North America on November 9, 2007, to negative
reviews and disappointing box office receipts.
The film explores themes of future, journalist, propaganda,
war on terror, externally controlled action.
The tone is uplifting and emotional.